Ian Dexter D. Marquez

Linux system administrator

+63 917 887 6260 im@iandexter.net http://www.iandexter.net

With more than 10 years extensive experience in administering Linux and Unix platforms. Develops and maintains various automation tools for infrastructure management and application deployment. Collaborates with global software development and operations teams in application delivery and support. Certified in Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Microsoft Windows, and ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management.

QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science in Computing major in Computer Science, 2011 Technological University of the Philip-

Technological University of the Philippines, Manila

Red Hat Certified Engineer, OCTOBER 2008 (NOT CURRENT)

ITIL v3 Foundation in IT Service Management, JULY 2008

Red Hat Certified Technician, November 2006

Microsoft Certified Professional, May 2006

Trend Micro Certified Security Expert, June 2006

Interests

DevOps, PaaS, IaaS, OpenShift, OpenStack, Google App Engine, Amazon Web Services

Skill areas

- Unix/Linux systems administration (10 years / advanced)
- Infrastructure automation (2 years / proficient)
- Application deployment and support (6 years / advanced)
- Network design, development and administration (5 years / proficient)
- Web design, development and management (3 years / proficient)
- Identity management (2 years / proficient)

Languages

- Bash/Shell (10 years / advanced)
- Perl (5 years / proficient)
- PHP (3 years / proficient)
- Python (2 years / proficient)
- SQL (2 years / proficient)
- Javascript (3 years / proficient)

Platforms

- Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, Fedora (10 years / advanced)
- SuSE Linux Enterprise Server (3 years / advanced)
- Ubuntu, Debian (2 years / proficient)
- Sun Solaris, IBM AIX (1 year / basic)
- Microsoft Windows 2003 Server (1 year / basic)

EXPERIENCE

Linux system administrator

APRIL 2010 TO PRESENT

Asian Development Bank (under RCG IT, Inc.)

Develops and maintains automation tools to manage the Unix infrastructure for the Bank's mission-critical applications like ERP, data warehousing, financials, and business intelligence. The Asian Development Bank is a multilateral financial institution that provides technical and financial assistance to developing countries.

Senior software engineer

MAY 2007 TO APRIL 2010

Accenture, Inc.

Supported the global directory services, identity management, and web infrastructure of a leading financial services firm. Accenture is an industry leader in global management consulting, technology services, and outsourcing.

Unix system administrator

JANUARY 2007 TO APRIL 2007

Asian Development Bank (under Cytronics, Inc.)

Operated and maintained Unix servers in the Bank's data center. The Asian Development Bank is a multilateral financial institution that provides technical and financial assistance to developing countries.

Systems engineer

APRIL 2006 TO JANUARY 2007

Trend Micro, Inc.

Provided intermediate-level technical and engineering support for Trend Micro enterprise products as part of its EMEA Technical Support Center infrastructure. Trend Micro is a global leader in anti-virus and security solutions, providing comprehensive enterprise-level services across multiple platforms and customer segments.

Linux and web administrator

JULY 2004 TO MARCH 2006

Philippine Rice Research Institute

Managed Linux servers of the corporate intranet in the local and wide area networks, and numerous web-based services for the Institute. Developed a portal for the Open Academy for Philippine Agriculture, the Pinoy Farmers' Internet. The Philippine Rice Research Institute is a premier research and development facility in Asia that pioneers and promotes rice science and technology.

Network administrator

APRIL 2002 TO JULY 2004

National Irrigation Administration

Designed and implemented the NIA Central Office local area network, and implemented services such as Active Directory, intranet, web, e-mail, and instant messaging. The National Irrigation Administration is the lead Philippine agency that provides irrigation services, development, operation and maintenance.

Community relations / information assistant February 1999 to March 2002

National Irrigation Administration

Implemented the public information infrastructure for the Casecnan Multipurpose Irrigation and Power Project (CMIPP), and frequently assigned to IT-related activities. The CMIPP is NIA's flagship project that provide irrigation services to northern Central Luzon and supplementary power to the Luzon grid of the National Power Corporation.